# **GREGORY W. MCGRATH**

P: (602) 463-1362 | E: greg@mcgrathq.com | W: https://greg.codes | LI: https://linkedin.com/in/gregmcgrath

#### SUMMARY

Dedicated and hardworking Senior Front-End Software Engineer with over ten years of experience creating captivating and high-quality web applications. Combines deep application development knowledge with strong capability building tailored software solutions, leading small teams, and delivering efficient results in fast-paced environments. Experience mentoring junior developers.

#### **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

JavaScript • React • Redux • Node.js • HTML5 • CSS3 • Express.js • Ext JS • Webpack • Babel • Git VS Code • Docker • Enzyme • Jest • Chai • jQuery • SQL • MongoDB • Java • Agile • Microsoft Suite

## EXPERIENCE

## Computer Technology Services | Clifton Park, NY Senior Software Engineer Consultant

2017 – Present

Leads the front-end development of Cengage's new Progressive Web Application (PWA) using React, Redux, Webpack, and Babel to replace legacy learning management system (LMS) for 2,500 daily ESL users. To increase student engagement I prioritized accessibility, internationalization, localization, and offline usage.

- Co-architected a scalable, secured API to transition from a monolithic application architecture into modern microservices; we delivered faster response rates, easier AWS deployments, improved data understanding, and support for multiple applications.
- Mentored two junior developers by conducting code reviews, helping them recognize effective code, encouraging beneficial learning paths, and teaching how to solve complex problems.
- Recognized and refactored common design elements into reusable, intuitive, and testable components, resulting in optimized performance, unified theme, partitioned complexity, and quicker bug-fix times.
- Implemented a continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) pipeline to increase deployment frequency, as well as improve consistency and confidence across multiple build environments.
- Participated in agile development process, including designing user interfaces, coding solutions, reviewing team's code, and estimating time and effort.

## TRANS WORLD ENTERTAINMENT | Albany, NY

#### Senior Web Application Developer

2016 - 2017

Led small team by promoting functional design patterns, requiring code reviews, and mentoring. Developed and supported essential retail applications and reporting using Node.js, JavaScript, MongoDB, Docker, and React Native.

- Coordinated with key stakeholders to create solutions like automated invoicing for unpaid subscriptions.
- Researched new technologies, built prototypes, and evangelized successes like ECMAScript 6 and CI/CD.
- Standardized ten diverse legacy projects to improve stability, reduce complexity, and increase agility.
- Translated product management's requirements into high-quality, timely deliverables.

#### STEWART'S SHOPS | Saratoga Springs, NY

#### Software Developer

2010 – 2016

- Trained eight-member team in best practices for architecture design patterns and ideal usage of Ext JS, as well as proposing new engineering productivity practices and tools.
- Developed and supported single-page applications providing sophisticated, tailored, and efficient solutions for 475 users.
- Spearheaded creation of a shared, tested code library to reduce development time of robust interfaces.

• Streamlined challenging corporate tasks by assessing needs, architecting solutions, and developing instinctive software solutions.

## INDEPENDENT CONSULTING | Remote

Full Stack Engineer

2013 – Present

- Completed independent, remote projects using Ext JS, PHP, and MySQL for diverse, international clients.
- Developed mobile-first user client for internet startup while collaborating with distributed team.
- Gained strong interpersonal skills by managing communication and workflow across simultaneous projects.

## EDUCATION

UNION COLLEGE | Schenectady, NY | Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering

2004 - 2008